## Ahmet OZKESEK

Ground Floor Flat 17 Stonor Road West Kensington W14 8RZ LONDON

M: 0772 922 3112

E: aozkesek@gmail.com

### **Profile**

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I developed, planned and designed various software for Contact Centre, ATM Management, Document Management and Workflow Management. I worked 16 years in Banking and Financial sector in Istanbul-Turkey, Now, I am seeking a Software Developer role in London where I can continue to improve myself in English.

# **Key Skills**

- Java 8 SE OCP Oracle Certified Professional https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8
- C#, C, JavaScript
- Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL Relational DB
- Junit, TestNG, Selenium Test Driven Development
- Gradle, Maven, Git, Docker
- Spring Framework Java EE, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces, Apache Struts, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- JTAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

# **Career History**

Oct 2016 - date	Istanbul - London	Freelancer
-----------------	-------------------	------------

- Self studying Java EE
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-ocp.pdf
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (94%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-oca.pdf
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application for Language Learning while Role Playing https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 from Nigeria. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm
  - http://ziezix360.com/about-us/
- Developed some application for improving in Java, TDD https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner

Jul 2014 – Aug 2016 NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant	
-------------------------------------	------------	--

- Designed and wrote Technical Design Document to submit a proposal for companies used Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program

https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program\_benefits/overview/index.gsp

https://downloads.avaya.com/css/P8/documents/101026461

- Developed an IIS Management web application for Cisco IP Phone Service <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager">https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager</a>

  https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager
- Trained the junior team members

Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
,	· ·	, <u> </u>

- Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months
- Developed and maintained workflow and document management service
- Developed and maintained automatic teller machine service
- Involved upgrading of contact centre infrastructure and hardware
- Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Aug 1999 - Aug 2001	Demirbank, Istanbul	Programmer
---------------------	---------------------	------------

Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

# **Qualifications**

- OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II, London, (1Z0-809, 81%, 2020-01-30)
- OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I, London, (1Z0-808, 94%, 2019-10-16)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: IP IVR Development Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: Java Server Pages, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified Developer
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: Internet Information Server (IIS), Active Server Page (ASP), Component Object Model (COM) Course

### Education

University of Istanbul, 1990 – 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (<a href="http://bilgisayar.muhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr">http://bilgisayar.muhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr</a>)